hello I'm your host David Bernard
today's conversation is shorter than
usual and will be featured in Revenue
cat state of subscription apps report
each episode in this series will explore
one crucial metric and share actionable
insights from Top subscription app
operators with me today Matt we
co-founder and CEO of photo room on the
podcast I talk with Matt about why some
apps see 30 times higher revenue on iOS
versus Android the challenges of running
a business on multiple platforms
and why you should consider offering a
free Android device to employees hey
Matt thanks so much for joining me on
the podcast thanks though it's been a
while yeah it has so I want to have you
on yall have been on both IOS and
Android since very early on and has seen
some really interesting things on the
Android side but I did want to kick off
on a higher level of just what are the
things you think about as a CEO running
a super fast growing app that's on both
Android and iOS you how do you think
about the differences between the two
major mobile platforms yeah it's a
question top of mind for a lot of topics
to give some context yeah for started
with iOS and later on went on to Android
I think it's one year later like iOS
2019 Android even
2021 so even like one year and a half
between the two high level I think the
big differences are when I think I think
iOS I think like a super penetration in
the American Market when I think about
under it I'm thinking about all the
other countries there it's like it's a
mix and some countries that are big for
mobile subscription like Brazil
southeast Asia even Europe where there's
a like a good mix and so I'm thinking
I'm actually thinking like some people
might be only focused in the US and in
this case I us makes sense if you're
like you care about localization you
want to launch in tons of countries then
Android you need to do like cond do iOS
only was there a lot of demand did you
hear from users like build us an Android
app I mean phot was still like kind of
MVP the tech was good but not as good as
it is now so it wasn't like I absolutely
need it yet I think when we started to
get traction on I think it was yeah eBay
early days as marketplaces when then
people we had influencers talking about
us and like people in the comments the
comments were I needed di on and Di and
iond Andro so I think when you start to
do marketing like you you feel like
you're paying for actually you pay for
some influencers and then all the
comments are when is's under R goinging
all that stuff so I remember that now so
you feel people are asking when you
start to eat product Market fit I think
before that you can tell yourself like
oh it would be better because then the
like variety Loop like the famous K
Factor all that stuff would be better
but I'm not sure it's like you don't
feel the pressure if you had to do it
over again would you have launched
simultaneously Android and iOS or do you
feel like it was it was better to go
ahead and kind of prove out the product
Market fit on iOS first yeah never never
like I would do exactly the same iOS and
then one hour two two years later
Android and I do think all the adopter
of apps as a general rule of thinking
would be more on iOS than Android and as
a like as a general rule but even more
so for the photo space photo video
category when you started to build up to
the launch on Android did you build up a
whole separate Android team and is that
how you run Android to this day is like
you spun up a whole separate team that
works in conjunction with the iOS team
yeah we have two different teams phot
the room so with time what we developed
is shared engine that is running like
the pixel rendering part so everything
that is pixel rendering and AI is common
we do have some native like device
algorithm that run on Apple that is very
I mean we didn't even try on Android
like it's too fragmented the hardware to
run yeah on device Mach running
inference but the engine is all the same
on iOS and now so how does that work out
today as far as are you still doing
earlier Explorations on one platform and
like you would maybe test something
first on iOS and then move it to Android
or now do you kind of more
simultaneously release on both platforms
or are you even like experimenting with
certain things that you think might work
better on Android on Android and then
bring him to iOS how do you manage that
development process we don't don't have
like a tightly loose specs where we want
to release everything at the same time
for all platform now I mean we have iOS
Android and even web now the way we
think about it is we need to run like a
mean it's like you have two legs like if
you really tie them together you don't
make like big steps we try to have some
flexibility to make sure we move fast
because that's the key to success for
startup and we kind of use like
resources when it's easier I do think
there are a few things where we try
where it makes more sense based on the
platform to try on different a version
so I don't know there are more
experiments or it's easier to track I
mean I give you an example you can
create a team in fot room and you can
invite someone for Apple it's you can't
really track because of privacy reason
through the App Store if you're inviting
someone so it's much easier to have a
good Benchmark of what would work what
would be the dream path on Android and
iOS so I mean we're we're not like uh we
depends on resources how big is the team
iOS team is bigger than Android so it's
usually it's iOS first but there are
some stuff where it makes more sense to
try Android that we would go Android
first and then how do you think about
monetization between the two platforms I
know this is something where photo room
is maybe a little bit unique from other
apps but how do you think broadly about
monetization amongst the two platforms
it's not exactly the same the two
platform what I remember quite clearly
is so I was at GoPro before and we it
was very challenging to have uh good
monetization on the under side and what
I learned is that there well at first
difficult to build a good video app on
Android it's the ipis from Apple are
really good on the video side and the
hardware is less fragmented like it's
not like there are some still some
device where you think there are some
gpus and they're not here or like it's
not plug in the right way Apple owns
hardware and software obviously is a bit
easier and then there's like I think
apple has a very like an amazing brand
on the photo side so if you're a photo
obest like the reality is you're
probably going to buy an iPhone like you
really pass about the about photography
and so what I noticed at GoPro is
basically you were doing like people
were doing 3x more revenue on average on
apps and there were like 2x more people
or maybe 4X more revenue and 2x more
people so basically it was 1 to 10 the
ratio of like a user the rpu by kind of
average when I was looking at some
benchmarks iOS to Android and then I dig
into the photos space basically the
ratio for photo apps was 30X so value of
a user on iOS was 30X bigger than
Android so that was a big learning
there's a lot of marketing from Apple
about like photography you actually if
you look at the keynote like it almost
as if like well we should call that the
camera more than and a phone now because
like that's the marketing cell that's
why a lot of the reasons why people
upgrade is because the camera got better
so if you're like taking photos of your
family it matters you want to spend time
on photography then you're probably
buying an iPhone especially in like the
biggest Market of all like the US and
that's like a huge that makes a huge
bias towards like people spending money
on the photo apps on the App Store
compared to the Play Store what happened
with photo room is like we got very
International and the most important
part is that people buy photo room
because photo room helped them make
money like we help your store grow we
help you as an e-commerce owner as an
entrepreneur as a restaurant owner to
have good quality imagery to like
present yourself on marketplaces on
social network in your emails and so I
mean as a business owner it doesn't
matter like there's no filter on your
iOS or Android person there's like
actually no bias and so that's why at
the end of the day like everyone is
working a lot of people have small
business owners there are a lot of them
in the world who are under it and so
they spend more they don't care they
just spend the money that the
subscription that make them like more
successful so there is no bias in that
and so we're much more successful like
relatively on the photo space on under
than the other apps that are like hugely
biased towards iOS and because of the
API also you see so many apps that never
went on Android so it's like it never
made sense economically for them where
it's very different for us you've
mentioned several times the
fragmentation of devices on Android and
the challenge is there do you have any
advice for folks who are building on
Android as far as like QA or like
minimum required specs for the app how
do you think about making sure that
people do have a good experience on
Android devices the best way to make
sure you have a good experience is it's
a very practical advice but I remember
the thing I did is like for a year or so
I I just switched as like a funer as we
were building the app to Android and so
I was like only using that to make sure
it's important and there is like a you
pay attention to details so that was
like a first very practical just like
remove your your sim card from your
iPhone by a good Android device and make
sure like you you test like it's dog
footing is the key and then keep in mind
also that like iOS people update and
upgrade their device to lat us OS a bit
more than an Android and Apple is really
good at that they always have like they
always give this like last feature that
is like fun that makes people move and I
think it's I don't know behind the scene
but I think they really care about that
and they advertise that a lot so yeah
keep in mind you can't like maybe on iOS
you can keep two versions of the major
Ros and Andro you need to keep a bit
more do you have a a separate QA team or
what what does quality assurance look
like on Android and and I mean do you
even have like does the Android team
have 20 or 30 devices that they test on
or how do you think about that that
quality assurance side of things for
Android we don't have QA at phot so
that's the one thing like everyone is in
charge of their own bugs and everyone is
using the app we do have a strong beta
test flight Android internal so these
are managed different ways but where
people like test the app for a week and
they have the latest feature but
sometimes it's Uggy and we look at the
analytics what's happening there is
anything weird we have some signals you
know I mean photo is lucky enough to
have like a product that is you can use
in your everyday life so we have people
using regularly and the team internally
using the app I you say like I want to
be fair with the Android team like one
of the difficult thing is the
distribution of iOS versus Android in
most tech companies is heavily biased
towards iOS so it's more it's much more
difficult to get people testing an
Android what we do give is like anyone
that wants an Android as phot employee
who on iOS and once's under and going to
use it or test it or try it or is a PM
which is you can have two device if
you're going to help the Android team
any other learnings that you've had now
operating on Android for almost 5 years
that you think folks could take away I
mean one of the challenge that we
haven't really solved is how do you you
solve for design and and you know
product because most people and most PMS
they would go on iOS at our scale I'm
sure like if you're 10x bigger you can
have someone that is specific you can
have a design that is specific to
Android but reality is like it's like
two different languages you know it's
two like you I mean you can take
Portuguese and Spanish like it it's some
and grammar is similar but some like
idec like expressions are different and
then you can make kind of a f or stuff
like this so give some freedom and make
sure that the Android team like
understand and that you you say know you
understand the the differences like I
mean the obvious example is a share icon
I had so much debate with the design
team and like a product about like the
designs and you you see this this little
arrow compared to the three circle like
the branching on under it that are that
is the share icon like people under they
don't understand the iOS icon and it
doesn't look native it's like you're
using a word in another language in
their platform so if you're making the
betat and that's for bed that like
native is better then yeah you need to
adapt and adapt the language and we
don't have two version of the designs
that one for iOS 400 so makes things a
bit difficult but yeah you have to allow
for this Freedom based on like the
native language any last tips that you
think people should be thinking about
and the differences between IOS and
Android there's one big thing that
people tend to forget is Apple is 30%
Commission on new subscription they have
like some people if you renew stay on
15% under is all 15% so it it does make
a difference for your margin especially
for like a company or margin like fot
room where you have like GPU costs for
machine learning and gen so it does does
make a difference yeah yeah I think a
lot of people forget that I forget that
often is 30% versus 15% you know and for
those you maybe aren't familiar with
this on Android Google made the decision
three or four years ago that just all
subscriptions it doesn't apply to to
games and consumables and single inap
purchases but on all subscriptions it's
15% across the board and as Matt was
alluding to on iOS once a user has
retained for more than a year you do get
bumped down to 15% but on initial
conversion that spread instantly gives
you more margin so definitely something
from a business perspective to be
thinking about it even if you're average
revenue per user is lower on Android
your margin is actually higher on those
pairs so yeah great tip for folks to be
keeping in mind yeah but build on under
is great too all right anything else you
wanted to share as we're wrapping up any
especially great roles you're hiring for
these days yeah yeah I mean we keep
growing and so we hiring both in
engineering both platform IOS and
Android and also so like we're hiring
for top of tunnel of the App Store like
if you're app store haer you know all
the details of that and you want to look
like very top of Fel of apps I actually
play with there are many things like act
new things use phot API to make
screenshots you know all these things
like it's a very interesting role
awesome all right Matt thanks so much
for joining me this is really
fascinating thanks for sharing your
insights thanks David it was a good
time thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. subclub
[Music]